Bibin Tom Joseph

Senior iOS Developer • 6+ Years' Experience in Swift

Summary

Experienced Senior iOS developer with a strong track record of delivering high-quality and user-friendly applications primarily using Swift and other relevant tools in a fast-paced and deadline-driven Agile Scrum environment.

Technical Stack (Checkout my work @ github.com/bibintomi)

Swift • Swift Packages / Cocoapods • UIKit / SwiftUI • Auto Layout using Storyboards / Programmatic UI • RxSwift / Combine • MVC / MVP / MVVM • CoreData • REST APIs & JSON • Agile / Scrum • Git • Jira • Debugging • Unit Testing Knowledge • Xcode

Work Experience

Accenture • April 2022 – Present

Application Development Senior Analyst

- Utilized RxSwift + MMVM to build complex and efficient payment interface, ensuring secure transactions and data privacy for customers to pay for gas at stations.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product managers, designers, and back-end developers, to ensure seamless integration of features.
- Mentored junior developers, conducted Code Reviews and provided technical guidance resulting in a 20% increase in development productivity.

HiFX IT & Media Services • February 2019 – March 2022

Mobile Application Developer - iOS

- Developed and maintained news, matrimony, and healthcare applications for clients, that have collectively received over 100,000 downloads in the App Store.
- Implemented code modularisation using cocoapods and Swift packages to increase maintainability and reuse, reducing development time and ensuring scalability.
- Improved app performance by 30% through optimization and code refactoring.
- Trained and mentored novice iOS developers, helping them to develop their technical and soft skills and grow within the company.

Digital Mesh Softech India P Ltd • November 2016 – December 2018 Associate Software Engineer

- Solely built a healthcare application and co-developed e-commerce application for clients, utilizing Swift and Xcode from creation to launch.
- Documented code using in-line comments and created technical documentation for the healthcare application.
- Conducted thorough testing and debugging to ensure high-quality delivery.

Education

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering

Karunya University (Coimbatore, India) • 2012 – 2016

Awards

Accenture PINNACLE Award FY22 - North Star

Awarded for driving an extra ordinary culture and leading my team to greater success with trust, collaboration and compassion.